A new breed of secret agent.
xXx is a action, adventure, thriller film directed by Rob Cohen.
Xander Cage is your standard adrenaline junkie
with no fear and a lousy attitude.
When the US Government "recruits" him to go on a
mission, he's not exactly thrilled.
His mission: to gather information on an organization that may just be
planning the destruction of the world, led by the nihilistic Yorgi.
Xander Cage, played by Vin Diesel.
Yelena, played by Asia Argento.
Yorgi, played by Marton Csokas.
Agent Augustus Gibbons, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Agent Toby Lee Shavers, played by Michael Roof.
Milan Sova, played by Richy Müller.
XXX (stylized as xXx and pronounced Triple X) is a 2002 American action
thriller film directed by Rob Cohen, produced by Neal H.
Moritz and written by Rich Wilkes.
The first installment in the xXx film series, the film stars Vin Diesel as Xander Cage, a thrill-seeking extreme
sports enthusiast, stuntman, and rebellious athlete-turned-reluctant spy for the National Security Agency.
Cage is sent on a dangerous mission to infiltrate a group of
potential Russian terrorists in Central Europe.
The film also stars Asia Argento, Marton Csokas, and Samuel L.
Cohen, Moritz, and Diesel had previously worked on The Fast and the Furious
(2001) as director, producer and cast member respectively.
The film grossed $277.4 million worldwide and was followed by two sequels, xXx:
State of the Union (2005) and xXx: Return of Xander Cage (2017).
The film explores themes of mission, biological weapon,
sports car, cold war, prague, czech republic.
The tone is emotional and intense.